Okay, so now I'm
going to show you
how to put a
pattern bank, which we
are then going to
turn into a ton
of ideas and our
strategy. And really, the
goal of doing this
is to research YouTube,
to find patterns that
work to grow channels,
so that we can
understand what buyers, viewers
love and what they
hate as well. And
then what we're going
to do is we're
going to build like
a minimum viable avatar
profile, which we're going
to ideate from. We're
going to use AI
and we're going to
use our own brains
as well to kind
of speed all of
this up. And the
process we're going to
go through looks like
this. So step one,
we're going to look
at our own channel
and we're just going
to look for what's
already worked, establish those
patterns. And this is
the quickest win. So
if you're an established
channel, you can pretty
much just repeat the
same patterns over and
over again. Then we're
going to examine the
niche and the niche
is going to give
us proven insights. So
it's going to show
us topics, titles, thumbnail
strategies, formats that our
ideal viewers really love.
And then we're going
to bring that back
to our channel. And
then we look at
the adjacent. So we're
going to look at
the niche, which is
going to enable us
to find kind of
patterns that make things
more interesting to people
and allow us to
differentiate. And we're going
to bring that back
to our channel. And
the patterns that we're
going to analyze are
these. So we're going
to look at topics
on our channel and
in our niche. Basically,
what subjects seem to
get the most views.
Titles. So the structure,
the words, power words,
as I call them.
So like emotionally impactful
words full of bends
that keep popping up
associated with views. We're
going to look at
thumbnail style. We can
look at thumbnail text.
We're going to look
at the formats to
establish what kind of
formats our viewers really
like. And we have
a little look at
production style too. But
the first step we're
going to go through
is researching our own
channel. So all we
want to do is
find out what viewers
love and what they
hate from your existing
channel and pay close
attention to your formats,
because not enough people
focus on the style
of video and reproducing
that. And for you
experienced channels, this is
going to be a
goldmine. So before we
go in to do
this, let me just
give you a quick
reminder of what we're
going to be doing.
So we're going to
start with what an
outlier is in case
you were not paying
attention in the last
video. You cheeky little
thingy.
So outliers are videos
that noticeably grew a
channel. So if it's
got like three times
the views of the
average video on that
channel, that's an outlier.
Anything above 2x usually.
So long as it
has a lot of
views for the niche.
And outliers are potentially
signs of what your
viewers want more of.
And we're going to
use a little robot
to help us do
this. So this is
the process I want
you to run through.
Step one. You highlight
your channel. So we're
going to pretend we're
Dimitri and we're a
drumming channel. So I'm
just going to highlight
our channel and I'm
going to scroll down
a couple of years.
We need a decent
viewer pool size. Like
don't put thousands of
videos into this thing.
Get back a couple
of years, I would
say. And then hit
copy. All right. And
then what we're going
to do, we go
to avatar research. We
paste that in. Hit
send. And it's going
to take a little
while to do its
thing. But eventually what
it's going to do
is it's going to
spit out this. So
it's breaking. Down the
patterns on the channel
for you, which you
are then going to
apply to a sheet
like this. So let
me just give you
a quick rundown of
what this looks like.
So it's going to
pull out the top
10 highest performing videos
from that selection and
then analyze them. Now,
what you need to
do is manually verify
this, too, because it
will make mistakes. Sometimes
it might miss things
out. But have a
quick look and go,
yeah, this looks about
right. Then it's going
to pull out the
power words, things like
genius, fast patterns, words
that keep repeating that
are associated with a
lot of views. So
you'll put them in
the power word list.
You'll put them in
the title list. By
the way, if you're
on a Mac, when
you copy this data,
what you want to
do is to make
it paste in a
line. Press shift control
option V and it'll
paste it down like
that. If you're on
a PC, buy a
Mac.
I'm going to use
the PC for years.
I can't actually advise
on that. Sorry. I'm
sure there's a.
You paid. You paid
money for this.
All right. Then it's
going to. Break down
patterns in the titles.
So not necessarily like
words, but what makes
the titles interesting to
viewers? So it picked
up on a use
of striking question or
statement with a twist
on common drumming errors
or works that direct
promises work. The inclusion
of well -known names
or bands does well.
So social hacking. So
we'll put that on
there, too, in the
title patterns. And then
we'll come in and
look at topics. So
improving drumming techniques and
hand speed, learning game
changing your own patterns.
Common. Practical demonstrations. And
then it will say
the most common video
length is around ten
minutes. So it's not
to say just make
ten minute long videos,
but it is telling
us something that this
channel is built on
shorter videos. So if
to meet you to
make a longer one,
we might find it
struggles because that is
not what the audience
has been built on.
Then it's going to
make a lot of
formats. So it roughly
knows based on the
title what format there
is. This is a
tutorial technique. So it's
basically a process video,
step by step, practical
drills and methods and
a breakdown and analysis
of other people's drumming.
Then we look at
things viewers hate. So
it's going to analyze
the flops and tell
you vague advice that
lacks clear, actionable drills.
Content that doesn't demonstrate
real improvement techniques. And
then it's going to
give you some titles
based on the outliers
with a slight tweak.
So old title was
this new title was
did this blunder make
Phil Collins a master?
They're not the best.
It's just to give
you some ideas on
how to reposition titles
yourself. And this is
very important here. Please
manually verify everything in
this list, which I'm
going to show you
how to do now.
So once we've done
that. We're going to
manually verify it. So
patent spotting is a
skill that you just
need to build. It's
really, really, really important.
And although AI is
great at this, if
you don't practice this
yourself, you're very reliant
on a robot and
not the good robot
in your head. And
that's the one that's
going to spot things.
It's going to grow
the channel too. So
let's have a look
at Dimitri's channel just
to do a quick
manual overview of this.
So we're going to
go down. We're going
to look what's performed
above average as an
outlier. This one here,
171 ,000 views. The
drum beat that changed
my life. It's already
on the list, so
I'm not going to
add it. But that's
interesting, right? It's like,
okay, maybe we could
use that title. So
we could put it
in the new title
idea bit here and
maybe change it to
the drum fill that
changed my life. So
it's similar. And then
let's keep going down.
We've got five easy
grooves that turn beginners
into pros. So I
like this. Easy. If
you think of big
bends, this is easy.
And it's got a
very specific result in
the title. So I
like that title. I'm
going to check. Is
it on our list?
There it is. If
it's not on the
list, just add it.
The technique beginner drummers.
Don't spend enough time
on. So if I
was Dimitri, I'd probably
thinking, how do I
repeat this in a
very similar way? So
it would be the
fill beginner drummers. Don't
spend enough time on.
And I'd probably just
have nobody told me
this pointing at a
slightly different type of
image. And that's the
idea. We'll manually go
through, look for problems,
things viewers hate, the
formats that seem to
work. And another thing
you can do is
you just go to
the most popular and
then have a look.
Right now, just keep
in mind when you
do this on some
channels that really established,
they're going to be
making videos for 20.
Years. Don't look at
the 20 year old
videos. Like I tend
to look at anything
within the last two
years because some stuff
can go out of
date. So yeah, I'd
be looking here and
going right. Mistakes, techniques,
clear results. These are
the patterns of what
works here. Clear result,
clear result, fast, fast.
So speed is the
thing that viewers love.
So I'd be thinking,
right. If I want
to make a video
that gets more views,
I'm going to take
one of these titles,
get lightning fast feet
with this simple hack.
I'd probably get get
lighting fast hands with
this simple hack. And
then what we're going
to need to do
is at the moment,
the AI from that
analysis isn't slick enough.
So we also want
to add this section
here from now patterns.
So what we need
to do is just
manually go in and
have a look at
the outliers and go,
right, where's this? Boom.
Hundred and seventy one
thousand views. Just play
this. Just play this.
One hundred and thirty
nine thousand views. You
see the pattern there.
So I'm going to
make sure I get
just play this down
on the sheet. I'm
also just going to
look at other sort
of things like Star.
Okay. So if you
look at the matrix
outliers, we've got social
hack did really well.
Curiosity. Stop this. What
does that mean? Nobody
told me this is
a curiosity based one.
This is a result
based one. Faster hands
in one week. This
is a curiosity like
what every day. So
if it makes you
go what, why or
how it's generally curiosity.
If it has a
result in it, it's
a result. So ten
times easier. That's the
result. Just play this
curiosity. This one's a
result, but it's also
a comparison, right? So
I'd be thinking, oh,
that's that comparison. One
did well looking at
the meat. She's allies.
He's not actually repeated
this much again. So
if I was Demetri,
I'd be thinking, right,
well, we need to
repeat. Stop this. Nobody
told me just play
this and probably more
comparisons because that one
went well. And I
haven't seen it again
here, but so that's
the name of the
game with researching your
own channel. You want
to do is build
it up onto the
sheet. And now if
you are new or
you're pivoting or you
don't have much data,
you don't mean to
see. Don't worry. Just
keep going with this
process because it doesn't
matter that much. Like
we're going to build
this pattern bank around
all sorts of different
things anyway. But if
you are an experienced
channel, the golden rule
is this. Anytime you
want to make a
video, the first thing
you want to do
is go to your
own channel to repeat
what works. And then
if you've repeated what
works too often and
you want to come
up with a new
idea, then read the
wider niche pattern bank
because it's just silly
not repeating already work
for us. And the
next thing we're going
to do is we're
going to go and
research the niche. And
what you need to
do is you want
to find five channels
and fill out the
same sheet for each.
Doing the same process.
And then after that,
we're going to build
one avatar profile, which
basically puts all of
this data together and
creates something we can
look at that gives
us a very good
overview of the avatars
loves and hates, which
we can then ideate
from. Thing is, how
do you find channels
to then research? Well,
there's a few different
ways. First things first,
just search your avatars
problem. Just type in
like play drums faster.
And then we can
see this channel here
from beats online. Nine
thousand subscribers. Lots of
views. This looks. Maybe
a good channel to
steal stuff from. So
that would go through
the process. The other
option is to go
to your audience. Also
watch. Right. So when
you click in analytics
and go to audience,
you'll see here there's
other channels that your
viewers are watching. So
remember how YouTube groups
your viewers together based
on their watch history.
This is what the
group it's feeding your
channel to is watching
as well. And we
want this audience also
watch to make sense.
I want to look
and go call Callaway
makes sense because he
teaches social media. Think
media does business. And
YouTube Grove Tom from
Alexander the creators presenting
on camera. Sunny does
exactly the same thing
as me. Where's does
marketing. So I'm like,
this is a great
place for me to
be having my content
fed. Now, if you're
new or small, you
won't have this. But
before you go and
research these channels, you
just want to click
on them and go,
is this the sort
of thing my avatar
be watching? Because sometimes
you are in the
wrong place and we
don't want to research
the wrong channels. So
there's a massive amount
of channels I could
research here. So click
on them. And look,
if you had. An
abundance of time, I
would say, do this
on every single one
of these channels and
find the patterns. But
I know you don't.
We're also can get
very overwhelming having a
huge amount of data
on your patent bank.
So I think five
is a good pool
to start. If you
have time and we
can squidge that up
to 10, that's going
to be great. But
let's start with five.
So that's the next
way. The other way
is to create a
dummy account. So the
way this works is
this. You basically start
a brand new YouTube
account. Don't post any
videos on it. But
go and watch what
you're. Avatar watches only
what your avatar is
going to watch. So
we would look at
drum speed videos. We
would go on one
of these channels that
we found like drum
beats online and we
watched like three videos
of theirs in a
row. We'd like we
could comment. We could
hit subscribe. We're going
to act like our
dream viewer does right.
And then find another
one. Now, look, when
you click on these
videos, what you're going
to see is down
the side. There's probably
more drumming stuff somewhere.
So Drumeo. So you
might just find there's
another channel we can
analyze here. Same thing.
Watch a few of
them. And what will
happen is this on
a say nine videos.
When you go on
the home page, YouTube's
then going to know
this is the type
of viewer that goes
in this bucket with
all these other types
of viewers. Now, let's
start pushing them stuff
on the home page.
We think they're like
based on the viewing
behavior of similar people.
And you can then
scroll down here and
go, oh, look, Demetri's
popped up. Right. That's
cool. And you'll then
be able to find
other channels that you
might not have discovered
before. And this is
a great way to
find like up and
coming. And you can
then go on the
home page and you'll
see that there's a
lot of people that
are going to be
like, oh, look, Demetri's
popped up. And this
is where I like
to research. The other
benefit of doing this
is at some point
we want to see
your channel appear here.
And when your channel
appears on the home
page of your dummy
account, it's a great
thing because it means
YouTube knows what you're
all about. And it's
going to start pushing
your content to more
people like your avatar.
So we want to
end up on this
page. I highly recommend
doing this. It will
take up time. And
really, you should be
going in every day.
For 15 minutes, clicking
on videos your avatars
might like having a
bit of a watch.
The more content you
consume, the better you're
going to get this.
And we're going to
understand patterns and thumbnails
and so on. So
do that. The other
thing is one of
10. I'll do a
little tutorial on how
this works. It's a
software for helping you
find outliers, but it's
got a free Chrome
plug in which will
activate these little blobs.
So instead of you
having to manually work
out what an outlier
is on a channel,
it just puts the
number right. So 11
.9 X outlier. That's
one we want to
get on our sheet.
And I know this
is a four X.
We get that on
the sheet and analyze
this is a three
X. Get it on
the sheet and analyze.
So that's how you
can find different channels.
I do a mixture
of all of them.
But the game changer
for me when I
went from not being
able to grow to
absolutely blowing up was
this. It was when
I started to understand
patterns and what viewers
do and don't want.
So I can't recommend
spending time here enough.
So once we found
a channel, it's the
same process. So let's
say in Dimitri's niche.
Let's say. We found
this guy, right? He's
called Steven Taylor. So
the first thing I
find him and go,
oh, he's got a
lot of subscribers. That's
cool. All right. So
his views are kind
of low per subscriber.
That doesn't matter. We
just want to find
outliers like this one.
It's a 58 ,000
outlier. What else we
got? Let's keep scrolling.
70 ,000 views is
pretty good.
So he's got some
outliers on here. So
we'll do the same
thing. We're going to
highlight and then we're
going to paste into
the research bot. And
then the research bot
is going to give
us the data which
we can quickly analyze.
So. So same process
again. Manually check. Does
this look about right?
I find it a
lot easier to look
at the patterns like
this without all the
fun that was distracting.
So drum mistakes. Remember
from Dimitri's channel, one
of his best videos
was mistakes. Why this
three note drum technique
is genius. That did
really well. So we
can then look at
words of his love.
So mistakes kill finally
better cheat pro. Not
much is about speed
on this one, which
is interesting because Dimitri's
channel was rocking speed
really well. It's going
to go back and
manually check that. Cause
that seems a bit
unusual to me. So
doesn't actually look like
this guy is doing
speed. Some look at
his old ones. Now
some of his go
back years. We might
want to discount them,
but let's have a
look. Mistakes did really
well three years ago.
This comparison styles done
well from him. Yeah,
he's not done much
on speed. So maybe,
maybe he should be.
Then we look at
the title patterns. So
bold claims comparisons, cheap
versus expensive. So we
can, we'll note down
these on our sheet
in the same way
as we did before.
Like remember, it's very
simple. Just like that.
Then we look at
the top things. Viewers
love the formats. So
again, it's tutorials, step
-by -step drumming guys.
This guy's got reaction
and breakdown. So if
we look at Dimitri's,
the formats were step
-by -step that's the
same breakdown analysis. That's
the same and mistakes.
That's the same. So
we're seeing a pattern
here. Okay. Maybe there's
these three types of
videos we should be
trying out first. So
step -by -step could
be a short process
or a deep dive
breakdown or analysis is
basically a case study
or a reacts. And
mistakes videos is the
listicle. So after that,
we want to look
at the thumbnail patterns
again. So I will
eventually build an AI
that can do this,
but it wasn't good
enough yet for you
guys to use. So
what I'm going to
look at is text
first. So in these
outliers, what have we
got anything? This one,
learn drums, 10 days,
day one. So it's
kind of like results
based, but I don't
like series content like
this. It never does
very well. So I'm
going to ignore that.
How is this possible?
That did very well.
And it's a social
hack. So I would
note that down in
the thumbnail thing in
the thumbnail section, we'd
put in. Okay. Social
hack. What else do
we got? Why is
Steve again, analyzing someone
drum teacher reacts, analyzing
someone. So he's social
hacking a lot, insanely
simple approach to drumming
that works. So do
you remember Dimitri's title
structure earlier? It was
like five easy beginner.
Some things to get
a result. That's the
title structure that's working
here. Something easy to
getting a result viewers
want. So I'd maybe
note that down, but
let's keep going. Any
other patterns, huge mistake
pointing at something. So
that's the name of
the game. Now you're
going to do this.
I don't really recommend
your pattern sheet goes
too much bigger than
this, right? So you
can see I've got
gaps, but if you've
got a thousand things
on one channels, pantry,
you're not finding patterns.
You're just creating a
list. The idea is
to simplify this down
into some patterns. And
if you're worried, what
if I've missed some
doesn't matter. As long
as you found some,
that's fine. Cause we
need something to work
with to start. And
as you get better
at this over time,
you're going to start
to spot more things.
One more thing before
we move on to
the next step is
when we're analyzing. Pans
within our niche. What
we need to also
keep in mind is
this, right? So let's
use Alex for Moses
and example, cause I
see so many people
try and copy him.
So we could look
at Alex's channel and
go, if I wanted
to become a millionaire
in 2024, this is
what I do. Oh,
I'm going to make
a title like that.
Alex is famous for
being a millionaire. So
what happens is his
fans come in and
see this, give a
huge watch time that
then blast it to
more people like them.
You keep pushing it
because it's like the
data on this, the
viewer satisfaction is so
high. It's going to
force this video up.
But if we don't
have that back history
that people know about,
why is someone going
to click on an
hour long video of
us with some full
guide blueprint when they
don't know, like, or
trust us yet. So
you do want to
be a little bit
careful when you're doing
this sort of stuff
thinking would someone cold
actually listen to me
doing this and often
with her Mosey and
especially this style with
the tweet in it
doesn't work because. Well,
he has a Twitter
following. If you don't
have a Twitter following
and you're quoting one
of your tweets, it
doesn't work. So just
keep that in mind.
The just because it
works for one of
the biggest in your
niche doesn't necessarily mean
it could work for
you. Of course, we
test measure and refine.
So then the next
step is you're going
to create an avatar
profile based just on
your niche. All right.
So what that means
is let's say we've
got Dimitri's channel here.
We're going to go
to the brain and
we're going to dump
all the titles in
here. It's going to
delete that for now.
And then we're going
to go to the
other guy with his
outliers. I'm going to
dump all of his
titles in. Then we're
going to dump all
of the power. And
then all of the
title patterns, then all
of the top three
problems, then all of
the thumbnail patterns. And
we want to create
this spreadsheet with all
of the data in.
And then I want
you to paste that
into research bot, the
avatar research bot with
the prompt, create my
avatar profile.
So I'm just going
to assume this is
it, right? So it's
create my avatar profile.
I'm going to hit
send and then just
leave it a while.
It's going to take
a while to do
this thing. Okay. So
what that has now
done is it's taken.
All of the outlier
information. Okay. So it's
taken all of the
information from all of
those channels and it's
distilled it into the
top forming titles. You
just want to double
check them then across
all of them, what
it thinks the things
the viewers love most
is. So if it
noticed that on each
channel, the similar things
were appealing, similar thing,
similar title structures kept
popping up. It's going
to list them here.
If it noticed that
they had similar power
words, it's going to
list them here. It
basically gives weight to
the things that repeated
the most. And this
information that you are
now given. I would
make a new avatar
profile. I'm going to
go to my brain
document here. Just duplicate
it, put it in,
and you can use
this as something that
will now help you
make decisions. So anytime
you have an idea,
you can come in
here and go statistically,
is this what my
viewers love the most?
Or is it something
they hate? Or is
there a better title
structure or a better
type of video I
can make or a
better video length? So
don't just assume this
is always right and
it's not right right
now. It's something that,
and it's also something
that we develop and
build on over time.
So it's just the
start, but this should
help give you clarity
on direction. Okay. All
right. So then step
three, what we're going
to do is we're
going to research some
of the adjacent niches.
So for Dimitri, let's
say it's going to
be guitar. So guitar
play guitar. I'm just
going to put that
roughly in. It doesn't
really matter. Let's just
have a look in
search quickly. What can
we find this guy?
He's a, he's not
getting many views now,
so I'm not going
to look at him.
I want someone who's
got better views consistently.
What else? What else
have we got here?
All right. So we
knew drum mistakes were
good. So I'm going
to put guitar mistakes.
Let's just type something
in until we find
it. Ah, so we've
got Trey here. We've
got this person, 7
,000 subscribers, 187 ,000
views. Yeah. I like
the look of this
channel. What I'm going
to do here is
the same thing. I'm
just going to go
back a couple of
years and I'm going
to whack this into
research bot. Let's do
this thing. Now. What
you need to understand
here is we're going
to fill out the
sheet in the adjacent,
but we don't want
topics because this is
about guitar, which isn't
necessarily the same. So
we're not going to
copy what works in
chords. What we want
to look at is
title structures, power words,
title patterns. The problems
are not going to
be as relevant. And
then we're going to
get rid of things
viewers hate because that
might not necessarily be
relevant. It could be,
but we'll simplify it
and we're just going
to be left with
formats viewers love. Because
we might find a
pattern in the music
niche. It's basically all
about step -by -step
process, title patterns, powers,
allies, high was problems.
And then from now
patterns as well, we're
going to leave. And
what we want to
do is fill this
out. I'm just going
to do this manually.
It was the AI
is working in the
background. We could look
here and go, Oh,
tier ranking guitar skills
from easiest to hardest
tier list that did
well. So we could
maybe put that on
our title list. He
plays guitar so fast.
It makes me want
to quit. Now this
one's interesting. I would
definitely put this on
the list, right? Because
I'm going to paste
it like that. We
knew that drum speed
was appealing in the
drumming niche. So I'd
probably be thinking he
plays drums so fast.
It makes me want
to quit. And then
I'd be looking at,
all right, I got
humbled. I'd maybe put
that and do a
very similar style type
of thumbnail. And you
know what? It's like,
this is the sort
of thing we test.
So this one, everything
I know about playing
guitar fast again, speed,
it needs to be
working. And then we've
got this improve your
playing speed. So this
fun now we know
our niche is about
speed. So I'm looking
here going, right. I
could do drums, improve
your drum speed, hundreds
to 170 before and
after I probably clean
this up a little
bit, but look, we've
got this other, I
got humbled. Pat here.
So we're seeing patterns
with that work in
this niche. And then
that we've got some
big views here. Ultimate
major scale masterclass for
guitarists. So this is
an hour and it
worked practice this every
day. I like that.
So I'd maybe put,
excuse this hypo. I
put that in there.
Yeah. Skills intermediate guitar
should have. So that's
an interesting title, but
you know what? If
I go back to
vague motivation advice, lacking
clear action steps, skills,
intermediate. I think that's
a little vague. So
although that's an outlier,
I'm thinking, Hmm, and
actually no, it doesn't
demonstrate tangible improvement or
drill techniques. Like they
love step by step
tutorials and breakdown analysis.
And I think skills
into me cause I
should have maybe wouldn't
suit the avatar we
want. Now, of course
we're going to try
it just to confirm
what we think to
be true. But this
is why I like
having the, the hates
and loves in this
small document. We can
fast track stuff. So
how to improvise solos
on the guitar, the
hard way. Now that's
weird because the easy
way worked in the
drumming world. So we
could maybe have how
to improvise solos on
guitar, the easy way,
and then just have
drums like this actually
worth it. So hopefully
you can see what
I'm doing here. Let's
go back to the
avatar research bar. So,
okay. So what it's
done is it's, it's
put his outline.